Mita!
三田小姐
I have a favor to ask.
我有事要請妳幫忙
What is it?
什麼事？
This letter…
這封信…
Could you burn it?
能請妳燒掉嗎？
DIVORCE REGISTRATION
（離婚協議書）
I WOULD RATHER DIE THAN BE ABANDONED BY YOU
（我寧可死了，也不想被你拋棄）
Oh, no. I forgot my phone!
糟糕，手機忘記了！
You may think I'm a coward…
妳可能會覺得我很懦弱
But I've decided
但我決定
that I won't talk about what happened to my wife to the kids.
不要跟孩子們講我太太的事
When I think about how shocked they would be
我一想到如果他們知道
when they find out their mother committed suicide,
媽媽是自殺的，會有多震驚
I think keeping it a secret
就覺得別說出來
would be better for them.
對他們比較好
I understand.
知道了
Stop!
住手
Yui?
小結？
What did you just say, Dad?
爸，你剛剛說了什麼？
-Aren't you supposed to be at school? -Who cares about that now?
-妳不是去學校了嗎？ -現在那很重要嗎？
What is this?
這是什麼？
What is going on?
到底怎麼回事？
Say something, Dad!
你說話啊，爸！
Mr. Asuda.
主人
What? Oh, yes?
什麼？怎麼了？
If there is nothing else,
如果沒有別的事
I would like to continue with my work.
我想開始做我的工作了
Right…
這個…
Yes, please.
好，麻煩了
It was about a year ago.
大概一年前
Who is that person?
是誰？
It's my subordinate at the company.
是我公司的部下
I just couldn't live without her.
我就是離不開她
So I asked your mother if we can have a divorce.
所以我就問妳媽說可不可以離婚
Then,
然後
she left this letter in my bag the next day.
她隔天就在我包包留下了這封信
I WOULD RATHER DIE THAN BE ABANDONED BY YOU
（我寧可死了，也不想被你拋棄）
Then…
這麼說…
Did Mom commit suicide because of you, Dad?
媽是因為你才自殺的嗎，爸？
You even tried to abandon us.
你甚至還想拋棄我們
-You call yourself a father? -You've got it wrong…
-你還算是個爸爸嗎？ -不是這樣的…
I intended to fork out the alimony and pay for all your school expenses.
我有說我要付贍養費和你們的學費啊
-But you chose your mistress over us! -That's not what I…
-你為了第三者選擇拋下我們 -那也不是我願…
You killed Mom!
你殺了媽媽
Yet you continued living with us as if nothing is wrong!
還若無其事地和我們一起生活
If this wasn't exposed, you planned to hide it forever!
要不是被我發現，你還打算瞞一輩子
No, that's because I was thinking of you…
不是，我是為了你們著想…
I…
我…
Mom used to tell me…
媽媽跟我說過
"Your father must be having an affair."
“妳爸一定有外遇
"He's pretentious and he acts cold to me."
他裝模作樣，對我也很冷淡”
But I always tried
但我一直試著
to believe otherwise.
不去相信這是真的
But now…
但是現在…
I will never believe you again!
我絕對不會再相信你
Please, Yui!
小結，求求妳
Could you not let Kakeru and the others know about this?
妳可以不要跟小翔他們說這件事嗎？
They are still young.
他們還太小
If Kii finds out that her mom committed suicide…
要是希衣知道媽媽是自殺的
I don't know what she will do.
我不知道她會怎麼樣
Do me this favor, okay?
拜託妳了，好嗎？
Dad…
爸爸你…
You're dirty.
骯髒死了
You're dirty…
骯髒死了…
You should be ashamed!
下流無恥
Have a safe trip.
路上小心
Mita.
三田小姐
How could you burn something this important as if you didn't care?
妳為什麼可以這麼平靜地 燒掉重要的東西？
It's because I'm a housekeeper.
因為我是個家政婦
It is my job to do
我的工作
what my master instructs me to.
就是做主人要求的事
EISEI ACADEMY HIGH SCHOOL
（英成學園高等學校）
It's rare to see you late, Asuda.
阿須田同學，很少看見妳遲到呢
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Did something happen?
發生什麼事了嗎？
She probably stayed overnight somewhere.
她可能在外面過夜吧
She's flirting with one of our seniors recently, too.
她最近和一個高年級的在搞曖昧呢
What the hell are you doing?
妳幹什麼啊？
Hey, what are you doing?
喂，妳幹嘛？
Stop it right now!
給我馬上住手！
I understand that you must be suffering
我知道妳母親剛去世
because your mother just died.
所以妳很難過
But you have to get yourself together soon!
但妳應該要快點振作起來呀
You didn't do well in your last test either.
妳上次考試也沒考好
I heard you're in a relationship with Ozawa from Photography Club.
我聽說妳跟攝影社的小澤在交往
Is that true?
是真的嗎？
I hope you are not involved in indecent acts
我希望妳沒有做出
-unbefitting of a high school student-- -We're not!
-高中生不該做的事… -我們沒有！
Excuse me!
不好意思
Ms. Amano. I'll talk to Yui…
天野老師，我來跟小結…
I mean, I'll talk to Asuda about this.
我是說，我來跟阿須田同學談
Could you forgive her?
妳可以原諒她嗎？
Please!
拜託您了
CONTACTS
（聯絡人）
YUI
（小結）
Chief.
課長
We decided that
那麼我們的標語
this will be our slogan.
就決定是這個了
CREATING A TOWN TO PROTECT YOUR BELOVED FAMILY
（創造一個城鎮，守護最愛的家人）
Oh, this one looks good.
這個看起來很棒
All right.
好了
Let's do our best for tomorrow's presentation.
我們明天盡全力介紹吧
-Shall we have a drink tonight? -Oh, wow!
今晚要不要喝一杯？
My treat, of course.
當然是我請客
-Thank you for your treat, Chief.
-太棒了吧！ -謝謝課長
I'll go make a phone call first.
那我先打個電話
This is the Asuda residence.
這裡是阿須田家
Mita?
三田小姐嗎？
It's me.
是我
Excuse me,
那個…
but how are the kids?
孩子們還好嗎？
Kakeru is on his 13th consecutive loss playing basketball against the TV.
小翔在玩籃球電動遊戲 目前13連敗中
Kaito is taking a nap after struggling to solve a math question from cram school.
海斗解不出補習班的數學題目 現在在睡午覺
Kii is folding origami as she is unable
希衣在摺紙 因為哥哥們都沒空陪她玩
I got it!
我知道了！
PANDA
（熊貓）
Is that so?
這樣啊
Excuse me…
那個…
What about Yui?
那小結呢？
She is not home yet.
她還沒回家
So Kakeru and the others
所以小翔和其他人
are still not aware of that matter?
都還不知道那件事嗎？
What are you referring to?
您指的是什麼？
Right…
這個…
No, never mind.
沒事
Well, please let the kids know that I will be home late tonight.
那請幫我跟孩子們說 我今天會晚回家
Understood.
我知道了
Thanks.
謝謝妳
I really wanted to have a hamburger steak!
我一直好想吃漢堡排耶
No way. Me, too.
不會吧，我也是
Me, too!
我也是
How did you know we wanted to eat hamburger steak
妳又沒有問我們
when you didn't even ask us?
怎麼會知道我們想吃漢堡排？
That is my job as a housekeeper.
這是家政婦的工作
I'm digging in!
我開動了
-Thank you for the food.
-我開動了
No way.
不會吧？
What's wrong?
怎樣啦？
-Let me try yours! -Why should I?
-我喝喝看你的 -幹嘛啦？
Just let me try it!
就讓我喝喝看嘛
So hot!
-好燙 -你有病啊？
What?
什麼？
You're right.
真的耶
No way!
怎麼可能？
You realized that I can't eat hot stuff?
妳知道我不能喝太燙的東西？
That is my job as a housekeeper.
這是家政婦的工作
Mita can do everything.
三田小姐什麼都會做
Hey.
那麼
Can you fold a panda origami?
妳會摺熊貓嗎？
I can.
會的
Wow, this is incredible!
好厲害喔
Teach me how to do it!
教我怎麼做
As you wish.
我知道了
Seconds, please!
麻煩妳，我還要一碗
Understood.
好的
Hey.
喂
You guys think she's married?
你們覺得她結婚了嗎？
Why don't you ask if you're interested?
你想知道不會自己問嗎？
You do it!
你去問啦
Hey. Are you married, Mita?
嘿，三田小姐，妳結婚了嗎？
Hey!
喂！
I apologize,
我很抱歉
but I can't reveal any personal information.
我無法透露個人資訊
-Kakeru. -Yes?
-小翔 -怎麼了？
Could you take off your shorts later?
你等等可以把短褲脫掉嗎？
What?
什麼？
The button is about to come undone, so I will sew it back up.
鈕扣快掉了，我要把它縫好
Why are you getting embarrassed?
你幹嘛那麼尷尬？
Shut up!
吵死了啦
Mita.
三田小姐
Could you bathe with me today?
今天能陪我泡澡嗎？
As you wish.
沒問題
-After climbing up -After climbing up.
-爬上這座
-This slope -This slope.
-山丘之後
There's a tree
往右邊走
-There's a tree. -What are you doing?
-往右邊走 -你們在幹嘛啊？
To the right
有一棵樹
No, nothing.
沒事，沒什麼啊
We're supposed to ask that! Why are you back so late?
妳才是，怎麼這麼晚回來？
Hey! Are you ignoring me?
喂，幹嘛不理我？
I WOULD RATHER DIE THAN BE ABANDONED BY YOU
（我寧可死了，也不想被你拋棄）
Come in.
請進
Welcome home.
歡迎回家
Hey.
是的
What will you have for dinner?
您晚餐想吃什麼呢？
I'm fine, I had dinner already.
不用了，我已經吃過了
If that is the case, I will leave once I put Kii to bed.
這樣的話，我等希衣睡著後就會離開
Excuse me.
那個
Where's Dad?
爸呢？
He will be home late.
他今天會晚回家
I see.
這樣啊
Hey.
喂
What do you think, Yui?
姐，妳怎麼想？
What? About what?
什麼？想什麼？
About Mita!
三田小姐啊
You think she's married?
妳覺得她結婚了嗎？
You think she has children?
妳覺得她有小孩嗎？
How should I know? Why are you asking?
我怎麼知道？幹嘛問這個？
I mean, we just can't tell what's on her mind at all!
因為我們完全看不出她的想法
She does everything we ask without any hesitation.
她都毫不猶豫地照我們的話去做
It's really odd!
很奇怪啊
The other day,
前幾天
she told me that she doesn't care if she dies.
她說她不在乎自己死去
I was planning to tail her
所以我打算跟蹤她
and check out where she lives.
調查她住在哪裡
Hey, what does "tail" mean?
“跟蹤”是什麼意思？
I'll explain it to you later.
我等等再跟妳解釋
Sorry,
不好意思
but I don't have time to play along with this ridiculous plan.
我沒時間參與你們荒唐的計畫
Hey…
等等
What's with that?
什麼意思啊？
Will you guys leave already? I'm going to change.
可以出去了嗎？我要換衣服
What's with that cold attitude?
幹嘛這麼冷漠啊？
Maybe she got dumped by her boyfriend.
她搞不好是被男朋友甩了
Stop talking nonsense!
你們別再胡說八道了
You guys don't even know anything.
你們根本什麼都不知道
What do you mean?
妳是什麼意思？
We don't know anything?
我們不知道什麼？
What's that?
什麼意思？
That's…
就是…
I'm not a kid,
我跟你們不一樣
unlike you guys.
我已經不是小孩了
So I have a lot on my mind!
所以有很多事要煩
Just go sleep already. Hurry up.
夠了，你們快去睡，快點啦
"Thank you very much."
“非常感謝你”
Dad is still not back yet?
爸還沒回來嗎？
Yes.
是的
Could you please give this to Mr. Asuda?
可以請妳轉交給主人嗎？
It's the invoice for today's overtime hours.
這是今天加班的收據
Please excuse me.
失陪了
Don't you think that…
三田小姐，妳不覺得
Dad is cruel, Mita?
爸很殘忍嗎？
You may be a housekeeper,
妳雖然是家政婦
but you're human.
但也是人
You should have your own opinion, right?
應該也有自己的意見，對吧？
I do not have the right to comment on other people's lives.
我沒資格對別人的人生發表意見
Fine.
好吧
Then I have a request for you, as our housekeeper.
那妳做為我們的家政婦，我有個請求
Could you go to Dad's company tomorrow,
妳明天可以去我爸的公司
and check out who Dad's mistress is?
確認他的外遇對象是誰嗎？
That person should take responsibility, too.
那個人也有責任
I want to know
我想知道
how that person is feeling right now.
那個人現在是怎麼想的
I'm sorry, but I cannot accept that request.
抱歉，我不能答應這個請求
What?
什麼？
Why?
為什麼？
Don't you do everything we ask?
妳不是什麼事都願意做嗎？
I am on leave tomorrow.
我明天請假
Good morning.
早安
Did I wake you up?
吵醒妳了嗎？
You don't need to go to school today, so you can sleep in.
今天不用上學，妳可以睡晚一點
Daddy.
爸爸
Why are you going to work when it's a holiday?
今天放假，你為什麼還要上班？
Didn't I tell you?
我沒說過嗎？
I don't work on Tuesdays and Wednesdays. Come on.
爸爸的公司是星期二和星期三放假
-Good morning.
-早啊 -早安
I'm hungry, Yui.
姐，我好餓喔
Is there anything to eat?
有東西可以吃嗎？
Scary.
好恐怖
She has been in a bad mood since yesterday.
她從昨天開始心情就不太好了
Do you know anything, Dad?
爸，你知道為什麼嗎？
What?
什麼？
It feels
這感覺好像
as if things were back to how it was before Mita came.
回到三田小姐來之前的時候喔
You should have Mita make something for us next time, Dad.
爸，你下次應該 請三田小姐做點吃的
What? Oh, yes. You're right.
什麼？對，你說得對
Right. Dad, do you know anything about Mita?
對了，爸，你知道 有關三田小姐的任何事嗎？
What?
什麼？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Like her address,
像是她的地址
or whether she's married.
或是結婚了沒之類的
Right…
這個嘛…
They can't reveal her information.
這些資訊他們不能講啦
-They have a duty of confidentiality. -I see.
-他們有保密的責任 -是喔
But the boss of the housekeeping agency told me something.
但是介紹所的所長倒是有說
It's not that she doesn't smile.
三田小姐不是不會笑
She just thinks that she can't smile.
而是她覺得自己不能笑
What did she mean by that?
那是什麼意思？
Could she have been involved in an affair?
她該不會在搞外遇吧？
And is that why she's so gloomy?
但她幹嘛那麼陰沉？
Daddy, what's an affair?
爸爸，“外遇”是什麼？
What?
什麼？
Tsubasa who lives next door told me about it.
住隔壁的小翼跟我說過
He said,
他說
"My dad is having an affair."
“我爸在搞外遇”
Kii.
希衣
An affair
外遇就是
is when a man with wife and kids gets involved
男人有了太太和小孩之後
in a relationship with another woman,
還跟另一個女人交往
and betrays his family.
背叛自己的家庭
Really?
真的嗎？
I feel so bad for Tsubasa.
小翼好可憐喔
I wonder what's going to happen if the lady next door
我很好奇要是隔壁太太 因無法接受而死
dies from the shock.
會發生什麼事呢
You won't do that. Right, Daddy?
爸爸，你不會這麼做的，對吧？
What?
什麼？
Oh, sorry.
抱歉
I need to go to the bathroom.
我要上個廁所
What?
什麼？
Hey, hold on!
喂，等等
I'm about to leak, too! You're not doing the big one, are you?
我也快尿出來了 你該不會是要上大號吧？
MIE KAZAMA
（風間美枝）
SENDER: MIE KAZAMA
（寄件者：風間美枝）
I'M FEELING SCARED ALL OF A SUDDEN SINCE YOUR WIFE DIED
（你太太死了讓我覺得很害怕）
I LOVE YOU BUT I THINK WE HAVE TO BREAK UP
（我愛你，但我們該分手了）
I have good monaka here. Want some?
我有好吃的最中餅，你們要吃嗎？
Forget about that. Will you tell us about Mita?
先別說那個了，妳能說說 三田小姐的事嗎？
Please, anything will do.
什麼都可以，拜託您了
You know, I can't say anything because of that.
你們也知道因為一件事，我不能說
Duty of confidentiality?
因為保密責任嗎？
Don't say that. Anything minor will do!
別這麼說嘛，任何小事都可以
I really love Mita!
我超喜歡三田小姐的
I love her, too!
我也很喜歡她
Dad told us about it,
爸爸有說
but does Mita really think that she's not allowed to smile?
但三田小姐真的認為自己不能笑嗎？
Well, you see…
是這樣的，她啊…
What do you mean by that?
什麼意思？
Actually…
事實上…
No, I can't!
不，我不能說
Could you guys stop trying to make me talk?
你們可以別再逼問我了嗎？
I worked as a housekeeper before, too.
我以前也是家政婦
So it's in my nature to prattle on.
所以我很會講八卦
Don't say that!
別那樣說嘛
We beg you!
我們求妳了
Hey, could you stop it?
嘿，可以別這樣嗎？
It has been a while since a young man made moves on me.
我已經很久沒被年輕小伙子追求了
My heart is beating so fast!
心跳得好快啊
Please!
拜託了
Why is Mita working as a housekeeper?
為什麼三田小姐要當家政婦？
You can ask her that yourself!
你們可以自己問她啊
She's about to come here soon.
她很快就會來了
She is really punctual, so she'll be here right on time.
她不會遲到，所以一定會準時來的
-Ten… -What?
-十… -什麼？
-Nine… -Hurry up!
-九… -快躲起來
-Sorry, don't tell Mita we're here! -We don't want her getting angry.
-抱歉，別跟三田小姐說我們在這 -我們不想惹她生氣
I know.
我知道了…
Five,
五
four, three, two, one.
四、三、二、一
Oh, my, Akari. What's the matter?
天啊，燈子，什麼事？
This is the referral commission for this month.
這是這個月的介紹費
Thank you as usual.
謝謝妳呢
You always give me yours punctually.
妳都很準時給我
Please excuse me.
那麼，我先告辭了
Wait, why don't you have some monaka?
等等，妳要不要吃最中餅？
Isn't that your favorite? Here, have one.
妳不是很愛吃嗎？來，吃一個嘛
No,
不
I'm fine.
不用了
Wait, Akari.
等等，燈子
Do you have any issues
這次妳負責的家庭
with the household you're currently working in?
有沒有任何問題呢？
With the children, perhaps.
像是小孩啊，之類的
No,
沒有
not really.
沒什麼問題
Come on out now. She has left already.
快出來，她離開了
Hurry and chase after her.
快去追她
If you hurry, you might be able to find out where she lives.
動作快的話，搞不好可以知道她住哪
-Thank you so much! -Don't mention it.
-非常感謝您！ -不客氣…
HARUMI HOUSEKEEPING AGENCY
（晴海家政婦介紹所）
All the best.
加油
An amusement park?
遊樂園？
Why?
她要幹嘛啊？
Okay. Let's go!
好了，我們走
-Did you bring any money? -What?
-你有帶錢嗎？ -什麼？
I brought some!
我有帶
Excuse me. I'm Kazama from Accounting Department.
不好意思，我是會計部的風間
Your visitor is over there.
您的訪客在那裡
Hello,
那個…
I'm Kazama.
我是風間
Could you be Chief's daughter?
妳該不會是課長的女兒吧？
Yes.
對
Do you need anything from me?
妳找我有什麼事嗎？
There's something I would like you to see.
我有東西要給妳看
I WOULD RATHER DIE THAN BE ABANDONED BY YOU
（我寧可死了，也不想被你拋棄）
What do you think of this?
妳有什麼想法？
Could you tell me…
妳可以跟我說
how you're feeling now?
妳現在的心情嗎？
You should also take responsibility for Mom's death!
我媽的死，妳應該也要負責
Yui!
小結！
-Did you tell him I'm coming? -I'm sorry.
-妳跟他說我會過來找妳嗎？ -我很抱歉
What are you doing, Yui?
小結，妳在幹嘛？
Let go! Don't touch me!
放手！不要碰我！
Anyway, let's go out and talk.
總之，我們去外面說
What are you doing? Let's go.
你在幹嘛啦？快走
Welcome. Good afternoon!
午安，歡迎光臨
CHILDREN STAR LAND
（兒童星樂園）
Thank you so much.
非常感謝您
Is she planning to eat all that by herself?
她要一個人吃完那些嗎？
Hey…
喂
What is Mita doing?
三田小姐在幹嘛啊？
There are two cups of cola,
她點了兩杯可樂
so maybe she's waiting for someone?
有可能在等人吧？
What?
什麼？
So she has a boyfriend?
所以她有男朋友嗎？
She didn't do anything wrong.
她沒有做錯任何事
It's all my fault.
都是我的錯
If you have something to say,
要是妳有話要說
why don't you just tell me about it directly?
為什麼不直接跟我說？
It's fine if you don't want to talk to me.
妳不想跟我說沒關係
If I get fired from the company,
但要是我被公司開除
I won't be able to take care of all of you.
我就沒辦法照顧你們了
Do you understand that?
妳懂嗎？
Just do whatever you like.
你想怎樣隨便你
What?
什麼？
That woman is probably
反正那個女的
more important to you compared to us, right?
應該比我們還重要吧？
No, I don't really…
不，我不是…
Hey!
喂！
Just what is going on?
到底是怎樣啊？
Anyway,
總之
We will be closing soon.
我們很快就要打烊了
She moved!
她動了！
Wake up, Kakeru!
小翔，快起床！
I'll do it.
我來就好
Thank you.
感謝您
Let's go, Kakeru! Hurry up!
小翔，我們走，快點！
She made a turn!
她轉彎了
What?
奇怪？
-Daddy! -Welcome home.
-爸爸 -歡迎回家
What's up? You're early today.
怎麼了？你今天比較早耶
Oh, I guess.
對，應該吧
Where have you guys been?
你們跑去哪了？
We were tailing Mita.
我們去跟蹤三田小姐
-What? -Kii!
-什麼？ -希衣！
Well, the thing is we happened to see her.
是這樣的，我們在路上碰巧遇到她
But we lost her immediately,
但我們馬上就跟丟了
so we couldn't find out about anything.
所以什麼也沒發現
Anyway, where's Yui?
不說這個了，姐呢？
What?
什麼？
-Did something happen between you and Yui? -What?
-你跟姐是不是發生什麼事了？ -什麼？
-What makes you say that? -Yui was acting strange this morning.
-怎麼說？ -姐今天早上怪怪的
Nothing happened between us.
我們沒什麼事啦
Forget that.
別說了
I ordered sushi,
我點了壽司
so go and wash your hands.
你們快去洗手
-Looks so good! -They look delicious!
-好好吃的樣子 -看起來好好吃
-All right! -Wait, I want to go first!
-好！ -等等，我要排第一個
Hello? Is it Yui?
喂？是小結嗎？
Oh, sorry. It's me.
姐夫，抱歉，是我
Did something happen to Yui?
小結怎麼了嗎？
What?
什麼？
No, not really.
沒事啊，沒什麼啦
Could you tell me if there's anything?
有事的話，可以跟我說嗎？
Yui was acting strange in school the other day, too.
前幾天，小結在學校也很奇怪
She was disrespectful towards her teacher.
她對老師很不尊重
Is that so?
這樣啊？
Just let me know if there's anything I can do!
有任何事需要我幫忙，你儘管說
I mean, things must be hard on you ever since Nagiko has gone.
姐姐過世後，你肯定也很辛苦
Sorry, but there's really nothing wrong.
什麼事情都沒有，抱歉
Maybe I shouldn't have called.
我果然不該打電話的
Don't scare me, Dad!
爸，你別嚇我啊
Why are you making a call secretly?
妳幹嘛鬼鬼祟祟地講電話？
I wasn't being secretive!
我沒有鬼鬼祟祟的
Why do you keep poking your nose into that family's business?
妳幹嘛一直插手那個家的事情？
It's because we're relatives, of course!
因為我們是親戚啊，很正常吧
Don't tell me…
妳該不會是…
You don't have any strange feelings for that man, do you?
對那個男的有什麼奇怪的感覺吧？
What kind of nonsense is that?
你在胡說八道什麼啊？
Give me a break already!
你夠了喔！
MOM: I'M SORRY, YUI.
（媽：小結，我很抱歉）
This is the last text your mom sent you?
這是妳媽傳給妳的最後一封簡訊嗎？
Until now…
我到現在…
I thought she was apologizing
都以為她是因為前一天跟我吵架
for the fight we had the day before she died.
在跟我道歉
I'M SORRY, YUI.
（小結，我很抱歉）
Mom killed herself
媽媽傳完這封簡訊後
after she sent me this text.
就自殺了
If only
要是…
Maybe Mom wouldn't have died.
說不定媽媽就不會死了
Mom always called me "my daughter".
媽總是叫我“女兒”
But this time,
但這次
she called me by my name.
她卻直接叫了我的名字
I did think it was odd.
我那時的確覺得很奇怪
But because we just had a fight…
但因為我們剛吵過架
I was annoyed…
所以我很煩躁
Asuda…
“阿…
Yui.
結”
Thanks, Daddy!
爸爸，謝謝你
Daddy.
爸爸
Do you love me?
你愛我嗎？
What?
什麼？
I love you the most in the world, too!
全世界我也最愛爸爸喔
Don't worry.
妳別擔心
My parents aren't home today.
我爸媽今天都不在家
Good morning.
早安
Mita.
三田小姐
Sorry, but…
那個…
Do you have some sort of hangover pills?
妳有宿醉之類的藥嗎？
I do.
有的
Mita.
三田小姐
Where's Yui?
小結在哪？
Yui.
小結
Hey.
喂
Where did you sleep yesterday?
妳昨晚睡在哪裡？
My boyfriend's house.
我男友家
What?
什麼？
I'm just doing
我只是在做
what you always do with your mistress.
跟你和你的情婦一樣的事情而已
Hey.
喂
What's with your attitude?
妳那是什麼態度？
How about
不如這樣
you stop acting like a father now?
你就別再裝成父親的樣子，好嗎？
You planned on abandoning us.
反正你也打算拋棄我們
-Stop that right-- -Just hit me.
-妳夠了… -你打啊
Unlike you,
我不像你
I did it with the person I love the most in the world!
我會跟我最愛的人做那件事
I won't love anyone else other than him!
除了他之外，我不會再愛上別人
I don't want to talk to anyone else other than him.
除了他之外，我不會跟別人說話
I think it will be wonderful if I can live with him forever!
我覺得跟他在一起一輩子 是最棒的事
What are you two doing?
你們兩個人在幹嘛？
Something really happened, right?
果然發生了什麼事吧？
Dad has been drinking more
爸最近也比以前
compared to usual, too.
酒喝得更多
Hey, Yui.
喂，姐
Ask that person.
你自己問他
No,
沒有
it's nothing.
沒什麼事
Mita, I don't need breakfast today.
三田小姐，我今天不吃早餐
I have an important presentation at the company, so I have to go early.
我公司有重要的報告，要早點去
Understood.
我知道了
Mr. Asuda.
主人
Your necktie is crooked.
您的領帶鬆了
Thanks.
謝謝
Have a safe trip.
路上小心
Okay.
好
Mita.
三田小姐
I have a request.
我有個請求
What is it?
什麼事？
Could you go to that man's company
妳可以去他的公司
and expose everything he did?
揭發他外遇的事嗎？
I will never forgive him
我絕不允許他
for always trying to worm his way out.
每次都狡猾地逃走
As you wish.
沒問題
TO KEIICHI
（惠一收）
In times like this,
在現今的時代
it is important to reconfirm our familial bonds.
加強家庭聯繫是很重要的
Thus, we decided on "Creating a town to protect your beloved family"
因此，我們決定用 “創造一個城鎮，守護最愛的家人”
as our slogan in promoting our new town project.
當作這次新城市計畫的標語
I think this looks good.
我覺得看起來很棒
Thank you.
謝謝您
Chief. A moment, please.
課長，不好意思
What is it?
什麼事？
Excuse me.
不好意思
This is bad.
不好了
Someone is giving this out in the lobby.
有人在大廳發這個
Keiichi Asuda from Business Department is having an affair
業務部的課長阿須田惠一
with Mie Kazama from Accounting Department since last year.
從去年起，跟會計部的風間美枝外遇
Because of that, Nagiko, Keiichi Asuda's wife, killed herself.
因為這樣，阿須田的妻子止子自殺了
In addition, he lied to his kids that their mother died in an accident.
而且，他跟孩子們謊稱媽媽死於意外
Hey! What are you doing?
喂！妳在做什麼？
Please don't do this in the building!
請不要在大樓裡做這種事
Keiichi Asuda from Business Department is having an affair
業務部的課長阿須田惠一
with Mie Kazama from Accounting Department since last year.
從去年起，跟會計部的風間美枝外遇
Because of that, Nagiko,
因為這樣
In addition, he lied to his kids that their mother died in an accident.
而且，他跟孩子們謊稱媽媽死於意外
Stop it, Mita!
住手，三田！
Excuse me.
不好意思…
Okay, done.
好，完成了
Welcome home.
歡迎回家
Thanks to you, they took me off the project.
都是因為妳，他們把我從計畫裡踢除
I might be transferred to the countryside.
我可能會被調去鄉下
What are you saying, Dad?
你在說什麼啊，爸？
What did you do, Yui?
姐，妳做了什麼？
I only
我只是
told the people in the company about
告訴公司的人
this man's true nature.
這個男人的真面目而已
What's that?
什麼意思？
I WOULD RATHER DIE THAN BE ABANDONED BY YOU
（我寧可死了，也不想被你拋棄）
Mita.
三田小姐
Repeat what you said at the company today.
請妳重複今天在公司說的話
Keiichi Asuda from Business Department is having an affair
業務部的課長阿須田惠一
with Mie Kazama from Accounting Department since last year.
從去年起，跟會計部的風間美枝外遇
Because of that, Nagiko, Keiichi Asuda's wife, killed herself.
因為這樣，阿須田的妻子止子自殺了
In addition, he lied to his kids that their mother died in an accident.
而且，他跟孩子們謊稱媽媽死於意外
What?
什麼？
What does that mean?
什麼意思？
Is that true, Dad?
爸，這是真的嗎？
Answer me!
你回答啊！
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Then,
也就是說
Mom's death wasn't an accident?
媽媽不是意外死亡的嗎？
I'm sorry.
對不起
You didn't even let the police see this letter?
你甚至沒把這封信交給警察吧？
If her death was ruled as an accident,
要是她的死可以被當成是意外
I thought it would be better for everyone.
我想這樣對大家都好
If you all knew your mother killed herself,
要是你們知道媽媽是自殺的
won't it be tough
這樣不會
to continue living?
讓你們活得更痛苦嗎？
Don't blame it on us!
別把錯推到我們身上！
She's right.
沒錯
You're just trying to protect yourself.
你只是在保護自己而已
I'm sorry.
對不起
Just stop apologizing to us already!
別只會一直說對不起
I…
我…
I'm tired.
我累了
What are you saying?
你在說什麼？
Ever since your mother died…
自從你們的媽媽過世後
I've tried my best to be a good father to everyone.
我一直努力當一個好爸爸
But I can't do it anymore.
但我不行了
What are you saying?
你在說些什麼？
It's just like your grandfather said.
就像你們的外公說的
-I don't have the right to be your father! -What the hell are you saying?
-我沒資格當你們的爸爸 -你到底在說什麼？
I don't even have the confidence to say I've loved your mother!
我甚至沒有自信 說我愛過你們的媽媽
Shut up!
閉嘴！
Stop, Kakeru!
小翔，住手！
Don't hit Daddy!
不要打爸爸！
Then, what should I do?
那我該怎麼做？
You guys…
你們…
Are you guys going to forgive him?
要原諒這個傢伙嗎？
Mita…
三田小姐
What do you think we should do?
妳覺得我們該怎麼辦？
That is…
那是…
something you should decide for yourself.
你們要自己決定的事
Everyone…
大家
Let's go.
我們走吧
What?
什麼？
There's nothing we can do but leave this house.
我們只能離開這個家了
But what about our belongings?
那我們的東西怎麼辦？
We can just get them sent to us later.
只能之後再請人幫我們寄過來
Come on, Kii. We're leaving.
來吧，希衣，我們走
Why?
為什麼？
You don't want to live with a man like him, right?
妳不想跟這種人住一起吧？
I don't want to leave.
我不想走
Daddy!
爸爸
Kii.
希衣
That man is no longer our father.
他已經不是我們的爸爸了
No!
不要！
Mita…
三田小姐…
Help me.
幫幫我
I cannot do it.
我沒辦法
What?
什麼？
I…
我…
am not your family.
不是妳的家人
I don't want this!
我不想要這樣
-Kii. Let's go. -No!
-希衣，走了啦 -不要
Hurry up, Kakeru and Kaito.
小翔和海斗，你們也動作快
Let's go, Kii.
希衣，走吧
You're not even trying to stop us
連這種時候
at a time like this?
你也不阻止我們嗎？
CREATING A TOWN TO PROTECT YOUR BELOVED FAMILY
（創造一個城鎮，守護最愛的家人）
How dare you act like nothing is wrong and create homes for others,
你為什麼可以若無其事 幫他人打造家庭
you pretentious bastard!
你這個虛偽的混蛋！
This is from Kii.
這是希衣給你的
She has been trying her best to fold it since yesterday,
她從昨天開始就很努力地摺紙
saying that she will give it to you first if she folds a good one.
說只要摺好了，就要第一個給你
DO YOU LIKE ME, DADDY? I LOVE YOU, DADDY!
（爸爸，你愛我嗎？）
Truth be told…
事實上
I didn't want to get married.
我那時不想結婚
But…
但是…
She was pregnant with Yui.
她懷了小結
My wife threatened me
我太太威脅我
that if I tell her to have an abortion,
要是我叫她墮胎
she'll kill herself.
她就要自殺
I wasn't sure if I could be a father.
我沒有自信能當一個好爸爸
I thought that I might change if I have my own child,
我以為有孩子之後，會有所改變
but nothing changed.
但我什麼都沒變
When I come home
每次我回家
and spend time with the kids,
跟孩子們相處時
I feel like they could see through my true self.
我都覺得他們會看到我的真面目
It felt so hard to breathe.
我覺得快喘不過氣了
I couldn't talk unless I forced myself to,
我連講話都覺得壓力很大
and the only places I felt at peace were in the washroom
我只有在廁所才能感到平靜
or in my car.
或是在我的車裡
It's time for me to leave.
我離開的時間到了
Please excuse me.
請恕我失陪
Wait. Just what's wrong with you?
等等，妳有什麼毛病啊？
You don't change your expression no matter what.
妳不管怎樣都面不改色
You do everything we ask,
不管提出多麼荒謬的指令
even if it's a ridiculous order.
妳都照做
Don't you have a heart?
妳到底有沒有心啊？
I don't.
我沒有
What?
什麼？
I lost that somewhere.
那種東西，我掉在某處了
You planned to destroy our family in the first place?
妳一開始就想毀掉我們家嗎？
Thank you for everything.
承蒙您的照顧了
I abducted Kii.
我綁架了希衣
What?
什麼？
-Just what is that housekeeper thinking? -I want to go home.
-那個家政婦在想什麼？ -我想回家
If you don't agree to my demands,
要是你不答應我的要求
Kii will die.
希衣就會死掉
Because of you, Kii is kidnapped!
都是你，希衣才會被綁架
I will never forgive him! I'll never acknowledge him as our father!
我絕不原諒他！ 我不會再把他當成爸爸
If you want her back,
要是你想要她回去
you have to agree to my terms.
就要同意我的條件
Stop this nonsense. Where is Kii?
夠了吧，希衣在哪？
-Kii!
-希衣！